Stefano Bovina

Curriculum Vitae

Via Ugo Foscolo 23 Pieve di Cento, Italy (+39) 347 0729632 bovy89@gmail.com
 bovy89@gmail.com

Summary

4+ years full-time working experience in IT operation.

Architect and operator of a deployment, monitoring and log analysis as a service solution.

Coding automation for orchestrating nodes and services deployment.

Passionate at advocating DevOps culture and tools.

Experience

Vocational

2012-Present System Administrator, Italian Institute for Nuclear Physics, Bologna.

Design and development of the Information System infrastructure, based on Ovirt virtualization manager, RedHat cluster and EMC VNX-5300 storage.

Detailed achievements:

- Setup and operation of
 - the node lifecycle management system based on Puppet and Foreman
 - the log analysis infrastructure based on ELK stack
 - the monitoring system based on Sensu, InfluxDB and Grafana
- Developing the infrastructure as code automations for all the operated services
- Hardening service security and configuration of mission critical web services
- o Installation and configuration of hardware parts in the datacenter
- Management of continuous integration environments and Docker images for production
- Administration of disaster recovery services

Miscellaneous

2012-Present **Developer**, Italian Institute for Nuclear Physics, Bologna.

Developer and member of support teams for several projects

Detailed achievements:

- Development of
 - the institute business travel management webapp, based on CakePHP framework
 - the institute Oracle EBS, a business applications for the enterprise
 - a webapp for suppliers documents management, based on Vaadin Framework and Alfresco
- Migration and upgrade of the entire information system from version Oracle E-Business Suite r.11 to version Oracle E-Business Suite r.12. First Italian Project with Oracle E-Business Suite r.12, in use in a public research institute.

Education

2008-Present Undergraduate in Computer Science, The University of Bologna, Bologna.

2003–2008 Diploma in Mathematics and Computer Science, I.S.I.T. Bassi Burgatti, Cento.

Technologies

Puppet, Foreman, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Sensu, Nagios, Zabbix, Redis, Git, Svn, RabbitMQ, HAProxy, Vagrant, Grafana, InfluxDB, Graphite, Dashing, Tomcat, Apache, Nginx, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Jenkins, Ant, Docker, Rundeck, RedHat, CentOS, OracleLinux, Debian, Ovirt, Jira, Trello, Nexpose, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Openoffice, Microsoft Office

Python, Bash, Ruby, PHP, Java, HTML5, CSS3, PL/SQL

Communication Skills

Passionate at elaborating and presenting technology research contents and outcomes especially in public speaking events such as conferences, workshops and tutorials.

Skills

- Attention to details in dealing with IT servers availability and reliability. I am currently coordinating the local computing centre provisioning and monitoring group.
- Experience in implementing helpdesk activity, incident response and problem solving
- Attitude at documenting and reporting both technical activities and working projects milestones/deliverables as well as using working group methodologies and tracking tools to analyse and prioritize tasks and issues.
- Passionate at scouting innovative technologies and tools.

Courses

Ethical Hacking, Overnet Education.

Network Security Administrators, Overnet Education.

PostgreSQL Administration and Performance Tuning, Cybertec.

Javascript new frontiers: TreeJs, AngularJS, NodeJS, Overnet Education.

Web applications with PHP and Mysql, Overnet Education.

HTML5 and CSS3. Overnet Education.

Spring Framework for Java applications, Overnet Education.

Hibernate Framework for Java applications, Overnet Education.

Oracle Database: Program with PL/SQL, Oracle University.

Awards

2005 First place at "Concorso Paolo Bongiovanni: Best website" 2005 edition

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English Intermediate

Interests

- Snowboarding

- Motorcycling

- Music

- Videogame